ABIOLA AROBIEKE

FULL STACK WFB DEVELOPER

abiola.arobieke@gmail.com | Github | Linkedin | Twitter | Portfolio

SUMMARY

A Ruby on Rails developer, with strong teamwork and problem-solving abilities. A software engineer with proven experience improving legacy code, code reviewing, mentoring junior developers, and building solutions for projects of all sizes. Fluent in React, Django, and Ruby on Rails.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, Vue, Vuex, HTML5, CSS3.

Back-End: Python, Flask, Django, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, MySQL, PostgreSQL.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools.

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Code Reviewing.

EXPERIENCE

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer) Feb 2023 – Present

- Mentoring junior web developers, and providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposing improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Providing advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.
- Mentoring junior web developers on how to set up JWT with Devise in Ruby on Rails.

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Full Stack Web Developer

Remote

Feb 2023 - Sep 2023

<u>Fast-Lane Racer</u> — A web app that allows users to make a car reservation.

Built with: Ruby on Rails, React, and Redux.

<u>Budget-It</u> — A budget planning app for registered users. Users can add a new budget category and its expense item.

Built with: Ruby on Rails, HTML, and CSS.

<u>FX-Today</u> — A foreign exchange app built for mobile screens. Rates are updated in real-time based on FX-interbank.

• Built with: React, Redux, and Redux-Thunk.

<u>Pasanova BookStore</u> — An e-book store that allows users to read books and keep track of their reading progress.

• Built with: React, Redux, and Redux-Thunk.

USTACKY

Lagos, Nigeria Jan 2021 – Jul 2021

Junior Developer

- Mentored intern developers on the use of Git, Flask, and Vue through over 30 virtual sessions.
- Promoted the usage of Trello board for seamless collaboration, task assignment, and real-time monitoring of developer progress.
- Led a team of intern developers by distributing tasks and coordinating efforts to ensure delivery is in alignment with the project requirements.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

Feb 2021 - Present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spend 600+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developing skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to

OLABISI ONABANJO UNIVERSITY

- Degree, Physics/Electronics
- Top graduating Physics/Electronics student 2017/2018.

Sep 2013 - July 2017